《超人4：和平任务》
要唱歌回家唱 辛纳屈同志
在家里 大家都叫我到外太空唱
在这里唱歌比较安全
(小镇)
(出售或出租)
请仔细听…
Listen carefully...
吾儿
... my son.
现在 凯尔…
By now, Kal-El...
你已经进入一个 叫做地球的星球的大气层
... you are entering the atmosphere of the planet known as Earth.
我祈祷你一路平安抵达
I pray you have made a safe journey.
你新家的黄色太阳 将赋予你巨大的能量
The yellow sun of your new home will give you great physical powers.
可是却不能抚慰你的心灵
But it cannot console your spirit.
这艘太空船上面装有个 能源小艇…
Placed aboard this vessel is an energy module...
装载一个曾经强大的文明 所遗留下来的一切
... all that remains of a once-powerful civilization:
也就是氪星 你的故乡
Krypton, your mother planet.
这是我送给你最后的礼物
It is my last gift to you.
只要拿掉这个礼物 这艘小艇就会冷却 沉寂…
Once removed, the ship will grow cold and silent...
然后此会完全剩下你一人
... and you will be finally alone.
小艇上的能量只能使用一次
The power in the module can be used but once.
务必谨慎使用 吾儿
Use it wisely, my son.
克拉克 你在吗？
Clark, you out here?
克拉克肯特
Clark Kent!
嗨 洪斯比先生
Hi, Mr. Hornsby.
在这边
Over here.
- 你在这里  - 你好吗 先生？
- There you are.  - How are you, sir?
- 我很好 克拉克 你呢？  - 很高兴又能见到你
- I'm fine, Clark. How are you?  - Nice to see you.
- 已经好久不见了  - 好久了
- It's been a long time.  - A long time.
你到的时候我正好在忙
I was tidying up for when you show the place.
我有没有跟你提到 有人连看都没看就说要买？
Didn't I mention there was an offer to buy, sight unseen?
我不想把这地方 卖给炒作土地的开发商
I don't want to sell this place to a big developer.
买家必须想买真正的农场才行 不可以再弄出一个购物中心
The buyer has to want a real farm, not another shopping center.
得了 克拉克 你为何如此固执？
Now darn it, Clark, why are you so stubborn?
现在已经没有人想买农场了
Today, nobody wants a farm.
你眨个眼睛 一切就全不见了 这才叫进化
You blink your eye and they'll all be gone. That's progress.
哦 我的天 看看这东西
Oh, my gosh, look at this.
哦 老强纳森肯特 是个爱开玩笑的人
Oh, what a joker old Jonathan Kent was.
有一次 我问他 这婴儿床怎么了
You know, I asked him what happened to the baby's crib.
他说…
And he said:
"一定是小克拉克 做恶梦时踢到了"
"Oh, little Clark must've had a bad dream and kicked it."
- 我发誓 我爸很喜欢讲笑话  - 对
- I swear, Dad liked a good joke.  - Yeah.
我想 也许你愿意代你的孙子 收下这些
I was wondering, maybe you'd like to keep these for your grandchildren.
哦 谢谢你了 克拉克
Why, thank you very much, Clark.
来 打一球
Here, batter up.
- 哦 不  - 好啦
- Oh, no.  - Come on.
- 不 真的…  - 我们打几球就好
- No, really...  - We'll hit a few.
小心了 我的球速很快的
Watch out now, these will come in pretty fast.
你就是打不到变化球
You never could hit a curve ball!
这是我对此地最终的决定
That's my final decision about the place.
我要保留给真正的农夫
I'm holding out for a real farmer.
是吗？
You are?
你真的跟你老爸一样顽固
And you're just as obstinate as your father was too.
我很抱歉 不过就是这样了
I'm sorry, but that's just the way it is.
你回大都会以后 要多多保重 克拉克
You be careful when you get back to Metropolis, Clark.
那是一个距离你的故乡 很远很远的地方
It's a long, long way from where you were born.
是的 先生 我谨记在心
Yes, sir. I never forget that, sir.
- 再见  - 再见 克拉克
- Bye.  - Bye, Clark.
你在吹什么 怪难听的噪音？
What is that God-awful noise you're making?
莫札特 我的猪脑袋朋友
Mozart, my low-forehead friend.
即使是在这悲惨的狗屎地方 也不能抹灭一个天才的心灵
Even this wretched pit can't diminish the spirit of true genius.
生命的源头来自一个 类似此地般根深的地带
Life itself started in a murky pit much like this.
像我这种真正的天才 就是能掌握当下
A true genius like myself learns to seize the moment.
你是第一个知道…
You're the first to know...
我有计划要再造新生命
...that I now have plans to re-create life itself.
路瑟 开始做工了 不然我们要把你丢去喂狼吃
Luthor, start breaking a sweat or we'll throw you to the wolves.
路瑟 也该搞脏你的衣服了
Luthor, let's get them duds dirty.
- 动作快点 猪头  - 认真一点
- Move it, meathead.  - Let's see a little sweat.
那辆车在这里做什么？!
What's that car doing here?
把那辆车给我拦下来
Stop that vehicle!
- 嘿 停  - 停下来 小鬼
- Hey, stop!  - Hold it there, son.
喂 这里是什么鬼地方 我要怎么去松柏市？
Yo! Where the hell is this and how the hell do I get to Cedar City?
你走错方向了 小鬼
You on the wrong side of the state, boy.
- 不会吧  - 哦 不
- No chance.  - Oh, no.
你的音响超好 超级棒的 小鬼
You got a fine, fine super-fine sound system here, son.
我想你们一定没见识过 这种百分百原音的环烧音响吧？
I guess you dudes have never seen one of these Sensurround 100s?
对 我在杂志上看过一次
Yeah, I seen one once in a magazine.
哦 快 上车来
Well, heck. Come on, get in.
- 真的？  - 快上
- Really?  - Come on.
真的？
Really?
- 你想听的 快上车  - 好吧
- You wanted to hear it, come on!  - All right.
上车 老土 我们来听一听
Hop in, Bubba. Let's give it a listen.
嘿 太棒了
Hey, this is great!
车门…
Doors...
怎么搞的？
What's going on?
车窗…
Windows...
- 怎么了？  - 车顶
- What's happening?  - The top.
座位
Seats!
天哪 天哪
Lordy! Lordy!
上路吧
And away!
欢迎你们再回来探望我们
Y'all come back and see us!
哦 不
Oh, no!
发射
Launch.
好耶
All right!
我的表现还可以吧 雷克斯伯伯？
Did I do okay or what, Uncle Lex?
蓝尼 你一向是我这家族里 无用的寄生菌
Lenny, you've always been the Dutch elm disease of my family tree.
不过这次 你做得很好
But this time you did fine.
你不想到处看看吗 伯伯？
You gonna skip the country, Uncle Lex?
你这公立学校出来的蠢东西…
You pathetic product of the public schools...
自从我被关之后…
...I've had nothing on my awesome mind...
我伟大的脑子里就只有一件事…
...since I've been incarcerated except one thing:
- 摧毁超人  - 摧毁超人
- Destroy Superman!  - Destroy Superman!
(大都会)
对不起
Sorry.
[法语]
克拉克
Clark!
(帮助我们 帮助你)
[法语]
(大都会捷运)
救命哪
Help!
救命 救命
Help! Help!
谁来救命
Somebody get help!
超人
Superman!
(让火炬永燃)
他没事的 看个医生就好
He's okay. He needs a doctor.
超人
Superman!
各位 请等一下
Gentlemen, one moment.
我希望大家都能了解 我们的地下铁系统…
I want people to know that our subway system...
是最安全也是最可靠的 大众交通工具
...is the safest and most reliable means of public transit.
谢谢大家
Thank you.
谢谢
Thanks.
你迟到了 肯特
You're late, Kent.
对不起 怀特先生 以后不会了
Sorry, Mr. White, won't happen again.
大家都上哪里去了？
Where is everybody?
无聊
Boring.
乏味
Tedious.
- 嘿 怎么一回事？  - 糟透了
- Hey, what's going on?  - Abominable!
- 你看 是大卫华菲尔  - 大卫华菲尔…
- Regardez, voil? David Warfield.  - David Warfield...
拥有那些三流小报的巨头？
...who owns those sleazy tabloids?
不对 是拥有那些三流小报 以及《星球日报》的人
Au contraire. Who owns all those sleazy tabloids and The Daily Planet.
乏味
Tedious.
你只看照片而已吗？
You only read the pictures?
怀特先生 事实上 我只读帐册
The fact is, Mr. White, that I only read the ledger.
是被我买下的 前一任的业主…
A ledger which the previous owners paid so little attention to...
根本没关心到的帐册
...I bought the paper from them.
这三年来《星球日报》根本没赚钱
The Daily Planet hasn't made any money in three years.
而我们这游戏的名称就是赚钱
And the name of the game is making money.
各位女士 各位先生 我的女儿 蕾西华菲尔
Ladies and gentlemen, my daughter, Lacy Warfield.
- 谢谢你 爸爸  - 很荣幸认识你
- Thanks, Daddy.  - It's nice to meet you.
怀特先生 蕾西将会协助你
Mr. White, Lacy will be helping you.
协助我？协助我什么？
Helping me? Helping me what?
我有带新版面的一些草稿来
I have some mock copies of our new layout.
很棒 不是吗？
It's super.Don't you think?
服装不太对 我们可以更正
The suit's not right, but we can change that.
对不起 华菲尔先生
Excuse me, Mr. Warfield.
世界并非真有毁灭的危机 这样的标题会不会太耸动了？
The world isn't really on the brink. Isn't that headline irresponsible?
也许 不过这样会很有卖点
Maybe, but it'll sell a lot of newspapers.
怀特先生 别冲动
Mr. White, don't do anything rash.
我不会让这家伟大的报社 变成你旗下的蠢货…
I won't let you turn this grand old lady into one of your bimbos...
怀特先生 容我指出 我爸爸拥有所有…
Mr. White, may I point out that Daddy holds all of your contracts...
你得遵守的合约
...which you will have to honor.
不好意思 你这娇娇女…
Excusez-moi, your spoiled-ness...
露易丝为什么老是讲法语？
Why is Lois speaking French?
我还得赶飞机到巴黎 去参加临时部长会议…
...I have a plane to catch to Paris for the emergency Ministers' Conference...
不用赶了 所有的出差全部取消
Not so fast. All trips are canceled.
你是说我到巴黎的旅行 取消了？
You mean my trip to Paris is canceled?
怀特先生 你跟我来一下
Mr. White, you come with me.
我要看你的帐册 其他的人全回去工作
I want to see your books. Everyone get back to work.
这对我们是不公平的 我要去找蕾西谈谈
We're not being treated fairly. I'm speaking to Lacy.
我也是
Me too.
抱歉 华菲尔小姐
Excuse me, Miss Warfield.
我代表全体向你说 我们会尽量地配合
I speak for us all when I say we'll do our best to cooperate.
谢谢你
Thank you.
可是记者的第一要务 是忠于真相
But a reporter's first allegiance is to the truth.
这座城市的人民仰赖我们 我们不能让他们失望
The people of this city depend on us and we can't let them down.
谢谢你
Thank you.
他是玩真的吗？
Is he for real?
百分百 我就喜欢他这点
100 percent, and I like him that way.
哦 你对他有好感
Oh, you have a thing for him.
对克拉克？没有
For Clark?! No!
他是有点可爱
He's kind of cute.
听我说 华菲尔小姐…
Look, Miss Warfield...
克拉克是现存最老的童子军 知道吗？
...Clark is the oldest living boy scout, okay?
他可信赖 他很愿意帮忙…
He's trustworthy, he's helpful...
他忠心 他很听话 他…
...he's loyal, he's obedient, he...
我不知道该怎么对你说
I don't know how to tell you this.
我认为他不会被你这样的女孩吸引
I just don't think he'd be attracted to somebody like you.
别傻了 全世界的男人都喜欢我 我可是很有钱的
Don't be silly. All men like me. I'm very, very rich!
你为什么没有出差的飞机旅费 肯特先生？
Why are there no air travel expenses for you, Mr. Kent?
我会晕机 尤其是遇到乱流的时候
I get airsick, especially when it's bumpy.
露易丝 进来
Lois, get in here!
露易丝 说明一下这一栏数字
Lois, explain this column of figures.
- 老编 总统要上现场了  - 什么 现在吗？
- The president is coming on live.  - What, right now?
- 一定不是好消息  - 你总是反应过度
- It won't be very good news.  - You always overreact.
- 没那么糟糕的  - 但愿很糟 莲恩小姐
- It won't be that terrible.  - Hopefully very terrible, Miss Lane.
有个国际危机 我们就可以创造两倍的发行量
We can double our circulation with an international crisis.
由于高峰会的失败…
And because the summit has failed...
我们别无选择 只好努力成为…
... we have no choice but to strive to be second to none...
核武竞赛的第一强国
... in the nuclear arms race.
因此 我在此宣布 如下方案…
Therefore, I am announcing the following measures...
我知道你们对于这个危机 感到很难过
I know you're all upset by the crisis.
我们也只能尽量往正面来思考
The best thing we can do is to try to think positively.
现在 我们能不能做什么？ 有没有人有什么建议的？
Now, is there anything we can do? Doesn't anyone have a suggestion?
好 我来建议好了
All right, I'll make a suggestion.
我们何不写信给我们的国会议员？
Why don't we write to our congressman?
- 没什么用的  - 人总得乐观一点
- That'll do a lot of good.  - Somebody has to be an optimist.
杰洛米？
Jeremy?
- 这种危机 我们该怎样？  - 他根本在状况外
- What could we do about the crisis?  - He doesn't know what's going on.
我知道可以写信给 真正能做事情的人
I know who I'd write a letter to that would do some good.
- 谁？圣诞老人吗？  - 不 超人
- Who? Santa Claus?  - No, Superman!
超人 也就是我们展览的主轴…
Superman, the subject of our exhibit...
他捐出一楼发丝给博物馆…
...has donated a strand of his hair to the museum...
好让我们得以观察他的神力
...so we can have the fun of seeing how strong he really is.
大家在此看到的 是一千磅的重物…
Here you see a 1000-pound load...
用他的一根头发就可轻易吊起
...easily suspended by his single hair.
博物馆即将关闭 所以我们行动应该快点
The museum will be closing soon, so we should hurry a little.
知道我用超人的一根发丝 能做出什么来吗？
Know what I can do with a single strand of Superman's hair?
做出一顶会飞的假发
You could make a toupee that flies.
这根发丝是超人的基因样本
That hair is a sample of Superman's genetic material.
是他那身躯的基础
The building blocks of his body.
以我的聪明才智加上足够的核能 就可以使基因突变…
With my genius and enough nuclear power to mutate the genes...
我可以创造出比他更有威力的人类
...I can create a being who's more powerful than him.
而且只忠于我
With total allegiance to me.
你最好退后 眼睛闭起来
You better stand back. Keep your eye out.
- 华菲尔小姐 你要见我吗？  - 嗨 克拉克 请进
- Miss Warfield, you wanted to see me?  - Hi, Clark. Please come in.
我有个很棒的好主意
I've come up with a brilliant idea.
哦 真的吗？
Oh, really?
至少我爸认为很棒
Well, Daddy thinks it's brilliant.
我要你写一个新的系列报导 就叫《下班后的大都会》
I want you to write a new series called "Metropolis After Hours."
叫谁 我吗？我…
Who, me? I...
是很棒 很好的点子 对不对？
It's wonderful. It's great, isn't it?
- 我不觉得这份差事适合我做  - 哦 你最适合了
- I don't think I'd be right for this.  - Oh, you're perfect for it.
我是说 你年轻 你单身 你很成功
I mean, you're young, you're single, you're successful.
我通常十点半说上床了
I'm usually in bed by 10:30.
就是这样 你不必引人注目
That's just it, see, you don't have to flaunt it.
我是说 你不是赶流行的人 不过…
I mean, you're no slave to fashion. Although...
- 你有没有想过戴隐形眼镜？  - 我的眼睛会痒
- ...have you ever thought of contacts?  - They make my eyes itch.
放心好了 我想我们可以合作
Don't worry about it. I thought we could do this together.
- 哦？  - 我知道所有合适的地点
- Oh?  - I know all the right places.
所有的夜间俱乐部 我都是会员
I'm a member of all the right clubs.
我们此从今夜的 大都会俱乐部开慕酒会开始
We'll start tonight at the opening of the Metro Club.
- 哦 今夜  - 对 就算约会了
- Oh, tonight.  - Yeah, it's a date.
约会
A date!
约会？
A date?
嗯 其实只是公事
Well, it's just business, actually.
我这里有一封要给超人的信 由我转交
I've got a letter here for Superman, care of me.
- 什么？  - 超人在这里收信？
- What?  - Superman gets mail here?
很可能是要照片的 我来处理
It's probably a picture request. I can take care of it.
我觉得这不只是一个超人迷的来信 你应该看看内容
I think it's more than just a fan letter. You should read it.
"亲爱的超人 我的老师 谈到总统核武竞赛的演讲
"Dear Superman, my teacher spoke about the president's speech on the arms race.
我们全都感到非常不快乐
We're all very unhappy about it.
我觉得我们应该请超人 为这世界去除所有的核武…
And I said we should get Superman to rid the world of nuclear arms...
因为只有他办得到
...because only he could do it.
一旦你摧毁所有的核武飞弹 大家此知道我是正确的
Once you've destroyed all the nuclear missiles, they'll see I'm right.
超人可以轻松迅速地 确保我们不把自己炸翻天
Superman can make sure we don't blow ourselves up, quick and easy.
我相信你会前来相助的 你的朋友 杰洛米敬上"
I know you'll come through. Your friend, Jeremy."
小鬼 哦 我最好快点回去工作了
Poor kid. Oh, well, I better get back to work.
- 不 这东西是有观点的  - 观点 他只是个小孩
- No, there's an angle in this.  - An angle! He's just a kid!
我老爸就喜欢这种煽情的活动 哦 天啊 社会大众也会爱死的
Daddy loves whipping up campaigns. Oh, boy, and the public loves it!
蕾西
Lacy!
我们要让他成为名人
We'll make him a celebrity.
世上的每一个人都会好奇 超人要如何答覆
Everybody in the world is gonna be wondering what Superman's reply is.
欢迎来到大都会 杰洛米
Welcome to Metropolis, Jeremy.
我是华菲尔先生 她是我的女儿蕾西华菲尔
I'm Mr. Warfield and this is my daughter, Lacy Warfield.
- 嗨 杰洛米  - 请过来跟媒体见面
- Hi, Jeremy.  - Now come along and meet the press.
- 你可别绊倒  - 我坐的车有个轮胎没气了
- Don't you trip.  - The car had a flat.
很抱歉听到这个小意外 转身
Sorry to hear that. Turn around.
让大家给你拍个照片
Let everybody get a picture of you.
- 此这样 各位  - 这边 杰洛米
- That's it, everyone.  - Here, Jeremy.
多俊的一个孩子 来…
What a boy! Now come along...
对美国大众说说 你刚刚对我说的话
...and tell the American public what you told me.
我说 我希望超人能答应我
I just said I wish Superman would've said yes.
- 你们听到了没？  - 没 我们没听到
- Did you get that?  - No, we didn't.
哦 再说一次 大声点
Well, say it again. Loudly.
我刚刚说 我希望超人能答应我
I just said I wish Superman would've just said yes!
(超人以沉默 回应小孩子)
莲 巴小姐
Miss Lane!
莲 巴小姐 看看这个 刚出炉的
Miss Lane. Take a look at this. Hot off the press.
哦 我的天
Oh, my God!
这一次他太过分了 你看 克拉克 你看这个
This time he's gone too far. Look, Clark. Look at that.
等不及要看我们家老编的反应了
Can't wait to see the chief's reaction.
我不想再当软柿子了
I'm through taking it lying down.
要找我的话 我在市中心
Anybody wants me, I'll be downtown.
老编是不是不太一样？
Chief look different to you?
就像我老爸 要去银行借钱的样子
He looks like my father when he went to the bank to ask for a loan.
我去确定他是否没事
I'm gonna make sure he's all right.
我们现在也没办法了 全看超人的决定
There's nothing we can do about it. It's Superman's decision now.
我相信他会做出正确的决定
I'm sure he'll do the right thing.
愿长者关照你…
May the elders watch over you...
吾儿
... my son.
他们的智慧 是一个曾经强大与先进的星球…
Their wisdom is all that is left of a once powerful...
仅剩的结晶
... and enlightened planet.
你一定得倾听他们的声音 凯尔
You must listen to them, Kal-El.
倾听
Listen.
我知道我不该干预
I know I'm forbidden to interfere.
但地球遭受到与氪星 相同的威胁
And yet the Earth is threatened by the same fate as Krypton's.
地球太原始了
The Earth is too primitive.
你可以逃到新的世界…
You can flee to new worlds...
到一个不再有战争的地方去
...where war is long forgotten.
如果你教导地球 把命运放在一个人的肩上…
If you teach the Earth to put its fate in any one man...
即使那个人是你 也等于是教导他们被人背叛
...even yourself, you're teaching them to be betrayed.
背叛…背叛…
Betrayed... betrayed...
背叛…背叛
...betrayed... betrayed!
由于高峰会的失败…
And because the summit has failed...
我们别无选择…
... we have no choice but to strive...
只好努力成为 核武竞赛的第一强国
... to be second to none in the nuclear arms race.
为达这个目的…
To that end...
本行政团队矢志追求…
... this administration has pursued...
且将持续追求…
... and will continue to pursue...
最有效的政策
... the most vigorous policy.
因此…
Therefore...
等一下
Just a minute.
- 露易丝？  - 你在 怎么了？
- Lois?  - There you are. What happened?
- 什么怎么了？  - 没什么 只不过…
- What do you mean, what happened?  - Nothing, just:
"六点大厅见 一起参加颁奖晚宴
"Meet in the lobby at 6 for the awards dinner.
正式穿着 不要迟到"
Wear something nice and don't be late."
- 难道你是对别的露易丝说的吗？  - 我很抱歉 我完全忘了
- Was it some other Lois?  - I'm sorry, I completely forgot.
好 你穿上你的燕尾服 我们出发了
Okay, go get your penguin suit on and we'll go.
如果你不介意的话 我不想去 我还有很多事得想一想
I'd rather not, if you don't mind. I've got a lot of thinking to do.
不过 你去吧 好吗？
But you go ahead. Okay?
克拉克？
Clark?
有什么麻烦吗？
Something's wrong, isn't it?
- 我能帮忙吗？  - 是的 事实上 你能帮忙
- Is there anything I can do?  - Yes, you can, as a matter of fact.
- 什么？  - 我们出去呼吸一下新群空气好吗？
- What?  - Could we go get some fresh air?
新群空气？
Fresh air?
新群空气 新鲜空气 当然
Fresh air. Fresh air, sure.
当然 克拉克 当然
Sure, Clark. Sure.
谁稀罕配菜一堆的好吃鸡肉呢？
Who needs chicken with all the fixings anyway?
咱们走 快 咱们去呼吸新鲜的空气
Let's go. Come on. Let's get some fresh air.
吸气 你觉得好一点了吗？
Breathe. Do you feel better?
克拉克？
Clark?
克拉克？克拉克 事情没那么糟 不要
Clark? Clark, things aren't that bad! Stop!
哦 克拉克
Oh, Clark!
克拉克 克拉克
Clark! Clark!
超人
Superman!
你还好吗？
You okay?
好极了
Great.
嘿 你看那边
Hey, look at that.
放手 拜拜啦
There you go. Bye-bye!
- 喜不喜欢一个人飞？  - 我喜欢
- How'd you like going solo?  - I loved it.
不过 更喜欢跟你一起飞翔
But not as much as being with you.
我也需要和你在一起 你给我带来欢笑
I needed to be with you too. You make me laugh.
你是唯一可以跟我谈的人 露易丝
You're the only one I can talk to, Lois.
有的时候我也不知道 该怎么做才好
See, sometimes I don't know what I'm supposed to do.
你永远可以来找我 你是知道的
I'm always here for you, you know that.
无论如何 你都会做出正确的决定 你一向都可以
And you'll do the right thing, no matter what. You always have.
谢谢你
Thank you.
- 你知道吗？  - 什么？
- You know something?  - What?
- 你甚至不晓得我的名字  - 凯尔
- You don't even know my name.  - Kal-El.
你记得的 不是吗？
You remember, don't you?
我记得一切
I remember everything.
"不要偏爱一人 要博爱全人类"
"Never set one of them above the rest. Love all humanity instead."
真是不公平
That's not fair.
露易丝
Lois.
露易丝 该走了 我们快迟到了
Lois, it's time to go. We'll be late.
我干嘛跑到外面来 冻死人了？
What am I doing out here freezing my butt off?
哦 你想要呼吸新鲜的空气
Oh, you wanted some fresh air.
哦 不 没关系 我可不要受冻威冒
Oh, no that's okay. I don't want to catch a cold.
我觉得怪怪的 好像有点虚脱的成觉
I feel kind of weird, like I'm jetlagged or something.
- 哎呀  - 我好像疯了
- Jeepers!  - Like I'm going crazy.
- 你呢？你的心情还不好吗？  - 没 事情很清楚了
- How about you? Are you still down?  - Nope. Things are pretty clear.
很好 想太多会让你没电的
Good. Too much thinking wears down your batteries.
克拉克 你得提起勇气向前走
Clark, you gotta go with your gut.
走了
Come on.
好 给你 杰洛米
Okay, here you go, Jeremy.
华菲尔先生想给你拍一些 带本地色彩的东西…
Mr. Warfield wants me to get shots of you with local color...
可是我还没什么点子
...but I can't think of anything.
- 嗨 杰洛米  - 超人
- Hi, Jeremy.  - Superman!
吉米
Jimmy.
我们的独家报导
What a scoop!
- 你想散散步吗？  - 当然
- How'd you like to take a walk?  - Sure!
吉米 走了
Jimmy, come on.
你不行 你的车会被拖吊的
You can't! You'll get towed.
你知道一张罚单要多少钱吗？
Do you know how much a ticket costs?
蕾西 钱财乃身外之物
Lacy, it's only money.
杰洛米 你可以在楼上的回廊等我吗？
Will you wait for me upstairs in the gallery?
当然好
Sure, okay.
- 祝你幸运 超人  - 谢谢
- Good luck, Superman.  - Thanks.
我帮你留了座位
I saved you a seat.
加油 超人
All right, Superman!
我不代表任何国家 不过我想向各位代表发言
I don't represent any country but I'd like to address the delegates.
哦 那你需要有与会国附议
Well, in that case, you will need a sponsor.
我想这样子就可以了 请
I believe that will do. Please.
谢谢你
Thank you.
他要说什么？
What's he gonna say?
说很好的事情
Something wonderful.
秘书长女士…
Madam Secretary...
各位可敬的代表 各位女士 各位先生
...honorable delegates, ladies and gentlemen.
多年来 我作为一个…
For many years now I've lived among you as...
与大家常在一起的过客 我欣赏你们许多文化的美
...a visitor. I've seen the beauty of your many cultures.
我成受到你们许多成就的喜悦
I've felt joy in your magnificent accomplishments.
我也见识到许多愚昧的战争
I've also seen the folly of your wars.
直到今天 我不再是一个过客 因为地球…
As of today I'm not a visitor anymore, because the Earth...
已经是我的家乡了
...is my home too.
我们不能活在恐惧中 我无法置身事外…
We can't live in fear. And I can't stand...
目睹我们疯狂的跌入…
...idly by and watch us stumble into the madness...
可能的核子毁灭危机
...of possible nuclear destruction.
我已经有了决定
I've come to a decision.
我要执行我们各个政府 不愿意或无法去执行的事情
I'm going to do what our governments have been unwilling to do.
从现在开始 我要着手去除 我们这星球所有的核子武器
Effective immediately, I'm going to rid our planet of all nuclear weapons.
好耶 超人
All right, Superman!
说得好 超人
Way to go, Superman!
飞弹初步测试 所有系统运作正常
Missile test Alpha, all systems go.
三 二 一
Three... two... one.
(发射)
哦
Oh!
哦 很高兴看到大家
Oh. Nice to see you guys!
你们何不放轻松 我来给大家介绍一下
Why don't you just relax there. I'll get on with the introductions:
迪丝
Dixie.
以及崔丝
And Trixie.
来自我们的自由大地 与透支王国的哈利霍乐
From the land of the free, the home of the great cost overrun, Harry Howler:
他是美国最高阶智库的 核武战略家
Nuclear strategist from America's top think tank.
也是独立作业的伟大战争贩子
And a great little warmonger in his own right.
接着 我们由衷欢迎 尚皮耶柏博斯
A hearty bienvenue to Jean-Pierre Dubois:
他是全球的核子弹头交易商
Nuclear warhead dealer to the world.
他的座右铭是…
His motto is:
"如果你不是向尚皮耶买的…
"If you didn't buy it from Jean-Pierre...
你就不是买到黑市价格"
...you didn't buy it on the black market."
罗莫夫将军
General Romoff.
许多人视你为"俄国疯子"
A lot of people think of you as the "Mad Russian."
我则视你为疯狂才子
I like to think of you as just madly eccentric.
请坐
Please be seated.
各位 我知道你们都感到激动 有点难以平复…
Look guys. I know you're all choked up, kind of overcome with joy...
超人终结武器竞赛 所带来的喜悦
...that Superman has ended the arms race.
不过 只要我们合作无问 我们此可以确保全世界…
But if we work together, we can make the world safe...
战争利润的安全
...for war profits.
麻烦你说重点
Get to the point.
重点在于 我 雷克斯路瑟 当代最伟大的犯罪者…
The point is, I, Lex Luthor, greatest criminal mind of the modern era...
已经找到一个摧毁超人的方法
...have found a way to destroy Superman.
请看 我严谨的好友…
Behold, my unscrupulous friends...
把窗帘关起来
Shut those blinds.
- 阳光刺痛我的眼  - 就是
- The sun is hurting my eyes!  - Exactly.
你知道太阳是什么吗？
You know what the sun is?
太阳只是一座巨大的核子弹…
It's nothing more than a huge nuclear bomb...
是一颗含有很多幅射能的炸弹 能将一个正常人化为灰烬
...a bomb with so much radiation, it'd incinerate the average man like that!
对 可是超人并非常人
Yes, but Superman is no average man.
啊 没错
Aha, right!
你有什么计划？
What is your plan?
各位 我这个老雷克斯 有个秘密配方…
Boys, old Lex here has kind of a secret recipe...
这道主菜可以称之为基因浓汤
...a genetic stew in this dish, if you will.
只要你们帮我把这东西 放在你们的一个飞弹上面…
If you'll help me put this on one of your missiles...
我可以保证 超人就会得到 他一生中最大的意外惊喜
...I promise you, Superman will have the biggest surprise of his life.
我要把他介绍给他的第一个噩梦 一个"核能超人"
I'll introduce him to his first nightmare, a "Nuclear Man."
他将会刺穿超人的皮肤 他将可让超人变常人 变病人
He'll pierce his skin. He'll make him mortal. He'll become sick.
我们将可在超人的坟上起舞
We'll dance on his grave.
我们干嘛跟你这种 恶名昭彰的坏蛋打交道？
Why should we deal with a notorious scoundrel like you?
别忘了我的座右铭…
Remember my motto:
"制造的恐惧愈多 换取的战利品说愈多"
"The more fear you make, the more loot you take."
卖出的飞弹也愈多…
And the more missiles you guys sell...
对 那对你有什么好处呢？
Yes, but what's in it for you?
就是小小的佣金
A tiny commission.
恰到好处的佣金
Something appropriate.
一个…
A number...
后面跟着很多零的数目
...with a lot of zeros behind it.
蓝尼
Lenny.
新的基因物质
The new genetic material.
小蓝尼…
And now, Leonard...
你的雷克斯伯伯…
...your Uncle Lex...
用这个从超人的头发细胞 培养出来的原生质…
...with this protoplasm that I have grown from Superman's hair cells...
就可以复制再生系统
...will duplicate creation itself.
纤维给我
Now the fabric.
伯伯 这一点点布是不够遮的
Uncle Lex, this ain't gonna cover him.
内部的电脑将会…
The computer inside will...
保留足够的材料 以维续我一向坚持的…
...leave enough material to maintain the high moral standards...
高道德标准
...that I've always subscribed to.
知道这代表什么吗 伯伯？
Know what this means, Uncle Lex?
什么？
What?
我们要为人父母了
We're gonna be parents.
(美国空军 梅森堡基地)
- 你叫什么名字 士官？  - 约克 长官
- What's your name, sergeant?  - York, sir.
稍息
At ease.
(美国空军)
发射控制组 是 长官
Launch control. Yes, sir.
是 长官
Yes, sir.
发生气候的问题 我们必须暂缓
There's a weather problem. We gotta hold.
暂缓？
Hold?
- 你叫什么名字 孩子？  - 哥伦
- What's your name, son?  - Goram.
要说"哥伦 长官"
"Goram, sir."
- 哥伦 长官  - 哥伦 你熟背你的规则簿吗？
- Goram, sir.  - Goram, you know your code book?
当然 长官
Of course, sir.
2706条 遇天候恶劣时 听我的命令发射 发射
2706, inclement override. Fire on my command. Fire.
是的 长官 准备发射
Yes, sir. Stand by to launch.
十 九…
Ten... nine...
没打到
Missed us.
伸展
Reach out.
快
Come on.
向下
Down.
向外
Reach out.
向上
And stretch.
下
Down.
上
Up.
- 克拉克 你还好吗？  - 我最好坐下来看就好
- Clark, are you okay?  - I think I better sit this one out.
真的要吗？这是你报导 大都会年轻人的好题材
You sure? This would be great for your series on the young Metropolis.
我们再试一次 来嘛
Let's try it again. Come on.
二 三 四
Two, three, four.
一 二 三
One, two, three.
- 我看不行  - 什么 你还好吧？
- I don't think so.  - What, are you okay?
28…
28...
29…
29...
33…
33...
- 可以了 很棒  - 好 现在轮你上
- Done. Great.  - Okay, you try it now.
- 我们帮你调高一点  - 好的
- Let's set it a little higher for you.  - Okay.
往下压就好了
Just push down.
- 你还好吧？快下来  - 需要帮忙吗？
- Are you okay? Just step down.  - Need some help?
你的朋友不了解自己的力量
Your friend doesn't know his own strength.
克拉克 这位是保罗
Clark, this is Paul.
- 他是这里的健身教练  - 很高兴见到你
- He's a trainer here.  - Hi.
嘿 我有最适合你用的
Hey, I got just the thing for you.
过来 小克
Over here, Clarky.
小克？
Clarky?
他真的很好 还想帮我
It's real nice of him to help me out.
- 他真的很行  - 来 试试这个
- He's really good.  - Here, try this one.
- 克拉克 你没事吧？ - 嗯  - 对不起
- Clark! Are you okay? - Yeah. - Sorry.
一分痛楚 一分收获
No pain, no gain.
真是一个浑球
Jeez, what a jerk.
我以前都不知道
Never realized it before.
我想我认识的很多人 都是浑球
I guess a lot of people I know are jerks.
也许你认为我也是个浑球 所以才一直迥避我
Maybe you think I'm one too. That's why you keep avoiding me.
哦 不会 我完全没这种想法 我只是比较忙而已
Oh, no, I don't think that at all. Just been really busy, that's all.
喂 等一等
But wait.
你知道露易丝要采访超人 谈谈他的和平任务
You know Lois is doing that interview with Superman about his peace mission.
嗯 我在想 我们四个人 正好可以一起喝个下午茶
Well, I was thinking the four of us can get together and have high tea.
这是很时髦的
It's very chic.
- 可以把那些哑铃给我吗 克拉克？  - 对不起
- Can you hand me those weights, Clark?  - Excuse me.
等一下 蕾西
Wait a minute, Lacy.
早点到 从我的阳台看出去 景致很浪漫的 再见了
Come early. The view is so romantic from my balcony. See you.
- 哦 当然 给你  - 不是那些 另一个
- Oh, sure. Here.  - Not those! The other one!
一分痛楚 一分收获？
No pain, no gain?
什么声音？
What was that?
雷克斯伯伯…你吓到我了
Uncle Lex... You're spooking me out.
来了
There.
夫人 非常成谢你
Madam, thank you very much.
我真是万能
I'm incredible.
雷克斯伯伯 他像…
Uncle Lex, he's like...
他很美丽 他很完美
He's beautiful. He's perfect.
欢迎回家 核能超人
Welcome home, Nuclear Man.
你的父亲很高兴见到你
Your father's happy to see you.
太阳的能量赋予他 内部自燃的热力
The power of the sun has given him internally generated heat.
我是一个…
I'm a...
你是…
You are...
我是…什么？我是一个天才？
I'm... What? I'm a genius?
我是万能的 我是…
I'm incredible. I'm...
你什么都不是
You are nothing.
现在我才是老子
I am the father now.
你有我的嗓音
You have my voice.
不 是你有我的嗓音
No, you have my voice.
别忘了 是我制造你的
Just remember, I made you.
对 你只是一个试验品 怪胎
Yeah, you're just an experiment, freako.
这是干什么？
What is that?
- 哦 糟了  - 我是试验品 我是怪胎
- Oh, no.  - I'm an experiment. I'm a freako.
我只是说怪胎只是在开玩笑的
I was just kidding about that freako line!
如果说这里有谁是怪胎的话 那一定是我了
If anybody's a freako around here, it's gotta be me!
哦 哇 我跳霹雳舞了 嘿
Oh, wow, I'm break dancing, hey!
酷毙了 嘿
This rocks. Hey!
我能创造你 我也能摧毁你
I made you. I can destroy you.
摧毁
Destroy.
现在就摧毁超人
Destroy Superman now.
你这可爱的孩子 但还不要 不
You sweet thing. But not quite yet, no.
过来 我们来讨论 什么时间比较适合
Come here. We'll discuss when the proper time is.
雷克斯伯伯
Uncle Lex.
哦 不
Oh, no!
他 就像…他冷掉了
He's, like... He's, like, cold.
当然是了
Of course he is.
这就是他的弱点 是唯一能阻止他的方法
That's his vulnerability. That's the only way he can be stopped.
什么？
What?
蓝尼 我的大嘴巴侄儿 他的能量来自太阳
Lenny, my loud-mouthed nephew, he gets his energy from the sun.
失去阳光 他说像夜间的你
Without it, he's like you at night:
一无是处
Useless.
没有十全十美的
Well, nobody's perfect.
我以前没参加过四人约会 很有趣 我看起来还可以吗？
I never had a double date before. This is fun. How do I look?
太性感了 就像你试穿过 那六套衣服一样
Illegal. Like the last six dresses you tried on.
听我说 蕾西？ 我不想扫你的兴或怎样 不过…
Listen, Lacy? I don't want to burst your bubble or anything but...
克拉克不会注意到你穿什么的
...Clark's not gonna notice what you're wearing.
会 他会 一定是克拉克
Yes, he will. There's Clark.
好 调整一下 可以了 你看起来棒透了
Okay, fix that. There you go. You look great.
- 也许只是超人来了  - 不会
- Maybe it's just Superman.  - No.
不会 超人的进场方式不一样
No, Superman makes a different kind of entrance.
- 嗨 蕾西  - 嗨 克拉克
- Hi, Lacy.  - Hi, Clark.
你有20块的零钱吗？ 司机没钱找零
Can you break a 20? Driver didn't have any change.
有 当然 我去拿我的皮包
Yeah, sure. Let me get my purse.
- 嗨 露易丝  - 嗨 克拉克
- Hi, Lois.  - Hi, Clark.
- 克拉克  - 什么？
- Clark.  - What?
你没办法相信的 这是华菲尔先生交给我问超人的…
You are not gonna believe this list of questions...
问题一长串 你自己看
...Mr. Warfield gave me to ask Superman. Look.
"你是否为降低我们国防的 一种阴谋？"
"Aren't you part of a plot to weaken our national defense?"
- 哦 我的天啊  - 我相信只有他的智商降低了…
- Oh, my goodness.  - I think his gray matter is...
- 我怎么能问他这种问题？  - 客气一点地问嘛
- How will I ask him these questions?  - Well, politely I guess.
我看看 我有18块钱 还有…
Let's see, I have 18 dollars and...
克拉克 她真的很喜欢你 你要注意她穿的衣服
Clark, she really likes you, so notice the dress.
我的美国运通卡
...my American Express card.
- 衣服  - 嘿 衣服很好
- Dress.  - Oh, hey, neat dress.
谢了 马上回来
Well, thanks. Be right back.
那是什么？
What's that?
那就是不同的进场方式
Now, there's a different kind of entrance.
- 嗨 露易丝  - 哈罗 超人
- Hi, Lois.  - Hello, Superman.
你好吗？
How are you?
我很好
I'm fine.
哦 超人 这位是蕾西华菲尔 她是老板的女儿
Oh, Superman, this is Lacy Warfield. She's the boss' daughter.
你好吗？你的衣服非常迷人
How do you do? That's a very attractive outfit.
- 我想我们最好开始访问了  - 失陪了
- I think we better start our interview.  - Excuse me.
双对同行
Two's company.
哦 对了 对 对 我去找克拉克
Oh, right, yeah. Yeah, I'll go get Clark.
他很可能在帮司机换轮胎 或在做什么善事
He's probably helping the driver change a tire, or some other good deed.
那家伙
That guy.
- 什么东西这么香  - 哦 谢谢你
- Something smells wonderful.  - Oh, thank you.
我在煮扇贝 还有鸭子…
I'm cooking some scallops and some duck...
全是用最棒的香结酱 香槟烹调的
...in this wonderful mushroom sauce with champagne.
以防我们事后肚子饿
In case we got hungry afterwards.
我是说 稍后
I mean, later.
你不必这么麻烦的
You shouldn't have gone to all that trouble.
我们可以进行访问了吗？
Should we get on with the interview?
好 我们 我们就进行访问了
Yes, let's. Let's get on with the interview.
你没收飞弹的行动 有任何麻烦吗？
Have you had any trouble confiscating the missiles?
总是有一些不正常的坏份子…
There always was the possibility that warped individuals...
想对打击这种全球的善举 不过…
...would take advantage of the world's goodwill, but...
有什么不对劲的吗？
Is there something wrong?
哦 我的晚餐 我的晚餐
Oh! My dinner! My dinner!
我 马上回来
I'll be right back.
马上回来
Be right back.
嗨
Hi.
- 我在想念你了 克拉克  - 哦 啊 嗯…
- I missed you, Clark.  - Oh. Ah, well...
跟露易丝 超人在一起很无聊 我们自己去疯一疯好了
It's so boring with Lois and Superman. Let's do something wild.
他们在等我们 这样很失礼
Gee, they're expecting us. It wouldn't be polite.
对 你对
Yeah, you're right.
一个人怎么能如此正直 却又如此诱人？
How can one man be so square and so delicious?
好 我们去聊天好了 如果我得去面对超人 那你也要
All right, let's go chitchat. If I have to face Superman, so do you.
蕾西？
Lacy?
哦 克拉克
Oh, Clark.
停
Stop!
我真是没办法相信 我从没做过 如此完美的烤鸭 太神奇了
I don't believe it! I never had duck turn out so perfectly. It's amazing!
我在外面 露易丝
I'm out here, Lois.
哦
Oh.
- 是不是很美？  - 对 是很美
- Isn't it beautiful?  - Yes, it is beautiful.
整个世界都很美
The whole world is beautiful.
我一直觉得像这么美好的时刻 就该与某一个…
I've always felt moments like this should be shared with someone you...
某一个你在乎的人共享
Someone you care a lot about.
那是门铃声吗？
Isn't that the doorbell?
对
Yes.
蕾西
Lacy!
克拉克人呢？
Where's Clark?
他原先是要走进电梯…
He started to get in the elevator...
哦 算了 说来话长
Oh, never mind, it's a long story.
克拉克老是这样
It always is with Clark.
哦 太好了 他来了
Oh, great, that's him.
- 克拉克？  - 嗨
- Clark?  - Hi.
男侍者得注意方向才行
Those bellboys ought to look where they're going.
超人？
Superman?
- 我很高兴你回来了  - 晚餐好了吗？可以吃了吗？
- I'm so glad you're back.  - Is dinner ready? Can we eat?
- 对 我们去坐下了  - 哦 太好了
- Yeah, let's go sit down.  - Oh, great.
- 对不起  - 我的天 不 没关系的
- Sorry!  - My goodness! No, that's okay.
不用弄了 克拉克 会沾到你的裤子上的
Just leave it there, Clark. It's stuck on your pants.
对 我去弄个抹布擦 对不起 马上回来
Yeah, let me just get a rag. Excuse me, be right back.
克拉克呢？
Where's Clark?
哈罗 超人娘子 哈罗 超人娘子
Hello, Dolly Hello, Dolly
很高兴我又能回到 属于我的天地
It's so nice to have me back Where I belong
别太在意 忧郁的男孩 只有你听得到我的声音
Don't be concerned, Blue Boy. You're the only one who can hear me.
这是我的私人频率 你可以称之为《雷克斯电视台》
It's my own private frequency. You might call it "Lex TV."
往你的左边看 高大 黝黑的师哥
Look to your left, tall, dark and handsome.
我打算将那栋大楼炸掉20层 误差值在一两层
I'm gonna blow 20 stories off that building, give or take a floor or two.
和平
Peace.
男人哪
Men.
但愿克拉克没事 我最好去看一下
I hope Clark's okay. I better look.
好
Okay.
很抱歉 不过临时有紧急的事 代我向华菲尔小姐道歉
I'm sorry, but an emergency's come up. My apologies to Miss Warfield.
哦 可是…
Oh, but...
超人 带我一起去 我可以顺便采访
Superman! Take me with you! I can cover the story!
你有看到克拉克吗？
You seen Clark?
猜猜我是谁？ 你的老朋友雷克斯
Guess who. It's your old friend Lex.
我想 如果你真的藏了炸弹 你早此逃得远远的了
I suspect if you'd actually planted a bomb, you'd be miles away by now.
这是我的侄儿蓝尼
This is my nephew Lenny.
他崇拜我
He worships me.
铁血汉子 哇 你这下子惨了
The dude of steel. Boy, are you gonna get it!
真笨 我还以为 我可以瞒过一个超级英雄
Silly me, thinking that I could fool a super guy.
你说对了 没有炸弹
You're right. No bomb.
只是你忙着做世界和平的事情…
It's just that you're so involved in this world peace bit...
根本没空拜访老朋友
...you don't have time for social calls.
我坦承 我骗你了
I confess, I tricked you.
你看起来很棒
You look great.
别客套了 你到底想干嘛？
Never mind the small talk. What are you up to?
你知道你是个工作狂吗？
You know you're a workaholic?
你一天24小时当好人
You're playing a good guy 24 hours a day.
何不停下脚步 闻闻玫瑰花香？
Why don't you stop and smell the roses?
或培养个嗜好？养只宠物？ 小猫 小狗这类的？
Get yourself a hobby? A pet? A kitten, a puppy?
大家都知道你讨厌小孩跟动物 你回大都会来干什么呢？
I know you hate children and animals. What are you doing back in Metropolis?
我想把在我们这里混的新角色 第一个介绍给你
I want to be first to introduce you to the new kid on the block.
仔细看看那细胞的结构
Look closely at the cell structure.
有没有看到什么眼熟的？
You see anything familiar?
你早此把人类的法律破坏殆尽
You've already broken all the laws of man.
现在又要破坏大自然的法则
Now you've broken the laws of nature too.
我只能推测你把某种装置藏在…
I can only assume you hid a device...
一枚被我抛入太阳的飞弹里
...in a missile I hurled into the sun.
肌肉男先生 我以后真的会很怀念 这些闲话家常的片段
Mr. Muscle, I'm gonna really miss these little chats we have together.
你是唯一跟得上我的智慧的人
You're the only one who can keep up with me.
- 蓝尼  - 干嘛？
- Lenny!  - What?
我想邀大家举杯致意
I wanna propose a toast.
敬一个好人 一个即将走到终点的好人
To a nice guy, who's about to finish last.
摧毁超人
Destroy Superman!
等一下
Later.
他有点迫不及待 你能怪他吗？
He's a little bit anxious. Can you blame him?
他可不是什么伟大的思想家
Not one of your great thinkers.
不过 在下我是
But I, in all modesty, am.
这个计划最成人的地方在于 是你协助我设计这个作品的
The touching thing about this plan is you helped me devise it.
牢狱生活使你的的思想 扭曲到一种狂乱的境界
Prison has twisted your mind into a delusional state.
不 不 不 听好
No, no, no. Listen.
我脱离牢狱时 脑子里只有清楚的一件事…
When I escaped from prison I had one thing on my mind:
超人之死
The end of Superman.
所以这是 我生命中…
So there I was, the first time in my life...
初次没有设计一个大规模 又是真正邪恶的犯罪计划
...that I didn't have a long-range, truly devious, criminal scheme.
然后 我想到了这个
And then I came up with it.
有了这家伙…
With this guy...
加上你又挂了…
...and you gone...
我就可以透过全球的再武装 赚大钱了
...I'll make a fortune rearming the world.
你为了个人的私利 让世界冒着核战的危机
You'd risk global nuclear war for your own personal financial gain.
没有人想要打仗的 我只是要让这种威胁存在
Nobody wants war. I just want to keep the threat alive.
俏皮吧？
Nifty, huh?
晚安了 王子阁下
Good night, sweet prince.
天下…
Parting is...
无不散筵席
...inevitable.
摧毁超人
Destroy Superman!
我要先玩一玩
First, I have fun.
救我
Help me!
谢谢你 超人
Thanks, Superman!
真是伟大的奇迹
没什么 祝大家愉快
我说过 我会让你经营一家 属于你自己的报社…
I said I'd get you to run one of our papers yourself...
我不是开玩笑的
...and I meant it.
(蕾西华菲尔出版社)
恭喜 发行人小姐
Congratulations, Miss Publisher.
谢谢你 爸爸 太好了
Thank you, Daddy, that's very nice.
请进你的办公室
Step into your office.
- 这是哪里来的？  - 有人送进来的
- Where'd this come from?  - Somebody brought it in.
我们买的 很便宜
We bought it, cheap.
好…这一次你真的太过分了
Okay... This time you've gone too far.
(超人已死)
你可以发行你的三流报纸 别想用露易丝莲恩的名字
You can print your stupid rag without Lois Lane.
你绝对没有权利拿这东西
And you certainly have no right to this!
- 露易丝 我很抱歉  - 让她走 亲爱的
- Lois, I'm sorry!  - Let her go, darling.
我是说 她没有利用价值了
I mean, she's useless.
你顺便也把克拉克肯特开除吧
And while you're at it, fire that Clark Kent.
他没来上班 他连电话都没打来
He hasn't been around. He hasn't even telephoned.
我知道 我也在担心他
I know, I'm worried about him.
哦 小猫咪…
Oh, kitten...
我们不是讨论过主管跟下属 别涉及什么关系了吗？
...didn't we have a talk about personal involvement with the help?
- 现在你可是发行人了…  - 爸爸
- Now that you're the publisher...  - Daddy.
- 是 亲爱的  - 给我住口
- Yes, darling.  - Stuff it!
露易丝 露易丝 我很抱歉
Lois! Lois, I'm sorry.
我保证 我跟此事无关
I promise you I had nothing to do with that.
你有克拉克的消息吗？
Have you heard from Clark?
没有
No.
等一下
Just a minute.
哦 露易丝
Oh, Lois.
- 你来做什么？  - 我就知道
- What are you doing here?  - I knew it.
我得了重感冒 你就知道 是什么意思？
I just have a really bad flu. What do you mean you knew it?
你怎么会知道？
How did you know?
你没去上班 你没打电话进办公室
You haven't been to work. You haven't called the office.
你连我的电话都不回 你怎么可以不回我的电话？
You haven't even called me back. How could you not call me back?
好吧 无论如何 我相信你有你的理由
Whatever it is, I guess you've got your reasons.
知道吗？我早知道你在这里
But I knew you were here, you know?
不知道怎么搞的…
Somehow...
就是有某种力量把我拉过来
...something pulled me here.
只要超人有麻烦 我就会知道
I always know when Superman's in trouble.
超人？他出什么事了？
Superman? Something's happened to him?
大家都说他死了 可是…
Everybody's saying that he's dead but...
不是真的 我说是知道 我的内心可以威受到
...that can't be true, I just know it. I feel it in my heart.
我想他只是需要协助而已
I think he just needs help.
无论他在哪里 露易丝 我相信他会撑过难关的
Wherever he is, Lois, I'm sure he'll manage.
嗯 如果他撑不过去…
Well, if he can't manage...
如果他真的有麻烦了…
...and if he really is in trouble...
那我有几件事想要告诉他
...then there's a few things I'd like to tell him.
我要告诉他…
I'd tell him...
我会永远珍惜与他共度的时光
...that I will always cherish the time we spent together.
我不会要求任何回报
And that I never expected anything in return.
无论…
And no matter...
我见到他的时间有多么短暂 我永远威到无比的快乐
...how few minutes I saw him for, it always made me happy.
我还要告诉他 我爱他…
And I would tell him that I love him...
我将永远爱着他
...and that I'll always love him.
还有…
And that...
无论…
...whatever...
世上发生什么事情…
...happens to the world...
我知道…
...I know that...
他已经尽力 要确保我们大家的安全了
...he's doing his best to make sure it's all right for the rest of us.
无论他人在哪里 露易丝…
Well, wherever he is, Lois...
我知道他会想要成谢你
...I know that he would want to thank you.
听我说 我很累了 知道吗？
Listen, I'm pretty tired, you know?
我想我还是在这里休息一下 好吗？
So I think I'll just rest here for a while. Okay?
我会好起来的
I'll be fine.
没关系的 好吗？
It's okay. Please?
- 希望你觉得好多了 克拉克  - 谢谢
- I hope you feel better, Clark.  - Thanks.
如果你有看到他 或听到他的消 急…
If you do see him, or hear from him...
他可能会需要这个
...he might need this.
哦 雷克斯
Oh, Lex.
我们很高兴你帮我们卖出去 那么多的…
We're all very pleased at all the nuclear missiles and arms...
核子飞弹与武器…
...you've helped us sell...
所以我们决定调高你的佣金
...and we've decided to increase your commission.
哦 各位 真的 太棒了
Oh, guys, really, that's great.
这是我们最起码能做的
It is the least we could do.
我有别的主意 各位先生…
Well, I had another idea. Gentlemen...
我决定要回去掌管公司
...I've decided to assume control of the company.
我的第一步正式行动 当然此是要说…
My first official act, of course, is to say:
"你们被炒鱿鱼了 "
"You're fired!"
你疯了
You're mad!
是吗？
Oh, really?
如果你们想要推荐函找工作…
If you want a reference for work...
别作梦
...forget it!
表演得很好
That's a good bit.
你知道 以我的智慧加上你的… 坦白说 你的…
You know with my brains, and your... Frankly, your...
肌肉 各种可能性都是很可观的
...brawn, the possibilities are absolutely staggering.
知道吗？我可以成为 总统 大帝或国王
You know, I could be president, emperor, king.
看到那些人有多害怕了吗？
See how scared those guys were?
那你怕什么呢？
And what do you fear?
什么？现在吗？超人死了 又有你在我的班底？
What? Now? With Superman dead, and you're on my team?
你就像是一股向前推进的动力 有什么好害怕的？
It's like you're the best power forward ever. What's to fear?
氪星所剩的能源全都是你的了
All that remains of Krypton's energy is yours.
在能源消失后…
After it is gone...
你就只属于你的新家园了
... you will belong solely to your new home.
如果我们垂死的星球 能拯救你的生命 吾儿…
If our dying planet can save your life, my son...
我们的死就有意义了
... we have not died in vain.
(你最爱的报刊的新发行人)
- 那个女人在哪里？  - 你永远找不到她的
- Where is the woman?  - You'll never find her.
如果你不告诉我 我就要伤害人类
If you will not tell me, I will hurt people.
住手 不要 人命关天
Stop! Don't do it, the people!
好了 住手 够了
All right, stop! That's enough!
够了
That's enough!
你赢了 我带你去找她
You win. I'll take you to her.
- 她在哪里？  - 安全遥远的地方
- Where is she?  - Far away from here and safe.
别进去 她不在那里面
Don't go in, she's not in there!
(危险 电梯绞缆室)
我们得润饰这些标题
We've gotta tone down these headlines.
润饰我们的标题？ 这些都是一般人爱看的
Tone down our headlines? That's all the common man reads!
- 我们可以别那么煽情  - 不煽情 报社就喝西北风了
- We can do with less sensationalism.  - Less sensational papers go broke.
我以为我老早说教过你了 报社的经营就是做生意
I thought I taught you long ago that the business of newspapers is business.
不 爸爸…
No, Daddy...
我们是做报导的
...our business is journalism.
我们不可以 老是这么不负责任…
We can't keep being so irresponsible...
不然我们会把大众导向灾难
...or we'll lead everyone into disaster.
别太戏剧化了 小姑娘
Don't be overdramatic, young lady.
我们哪有可能 带出什么大灾难？
What kind of disaster could we possibly help bring about?
蕾西
Lacy!
怎么搞的？嘿
What's going on? Hey!
(华菲尔出版社)
(星球日报)
你真的知道自己在做什么 怀特先生？
Are you sure you know what you're doing, Mr. White?
嗯…
Well...
华菲尔先生来了
Here comes Mr. Warfield.
你最好有很好的解释…
You better have a good explanation...
不然你就要在牢里 跟你的律师说话了
...or else you'll be talking to your lawyers from jail.
你知道 我不是什么巨头
You know, I'm not a tycoon.
我只是一个老记者
I'm just an old reporter.
不过我自己的报纸看很多了…
But I've read enough in my own newspaper...
我了解大公司恶意的接收
...about hostile takeovers at big companies.
你 华菲尔先生 一定是睡着了
You, Mr. Warfield, must have been asleep at the wheel.
因为我已经说服 这个城市的银行家…
Because I've convinced the bankers of this city...
我们的《星球日报》 应被视为一种天然资源加以保护…
...that our Daily Planet should be treated like a natural resource...
以免受到掠夺者的侵略
...protected from predators.
我说服他们把钱借给我 我买下多出来的股份
I convinced them to lend me the money. I bought the outstanding shares.
所以你 华菲尔先生 现在只是小股东
And you, Mr. Warfield, are now a minority shareholder.
大家回去工作了
Everyone, back to work.
说得好极了 老编
Way to tell him, chief!
我很抱歉 人总有输赢
Well, I'm sorry. You win some and you lose some.
这才叫报纸
Now this is what I call a newspaper.
致赠《星球日报》
Compliments of The Daily Planet.
- 祝你有美好的一天 我们成功了  - 我们又开张了
- Have a nice day. We did it!  - We're back!
- 嘿 我迟到了吗？  - 嗨 你还好吗？
- Hi, am I late?  - Hi, how you doing?
让你下病床来一定很不容易
It must've been some effort for you to drag yourself out of bed.
我觉得好多了 有一个很好的护士去看我
I'm feeling a lot better. I had a visit from a good nurse.
一定带了很好的药 因为她说你病得很重
It must've been good medicine because she said you were really ill.
有的时候 只要有正确的人 给予适当关注就行了
Sometimes all you need is loving attention from the right person.
很高兴你回来了 克拉克
Glad you're back, Clark.
别忘了 我要采访超人的记者会
And remember I am covering Superman's press conference.
- 你只要收录大众的反应就好  - 反应 好的
- Just tape reactions from the crowd.  - Reactions, okay.
哦 天啊
Oh, dear.
我想我需要一部录音机吧？
Guess I need a tape recorder, huh?
- 马上回来  - 克拉克
- Be right back.  - Clark.
克拉克还是老样子 改不了的
Same old Mr. Kent. He'll never change.
但愿如此
I hope not.
- 你好吗 超人？  - 露易丝 见到你真好
- How you doing, Superman?  - Lois, good to see you again.
我也是
Good to see you too.
早安 各位先生
Morning, gentlemen.
抱歉
Excuse me.
谢谢大家
Thank you.
再一次 我们渡过战争的威胁 又找回脆弱的和平
Once more, we survived the threat of war and found a fragile peace.
我曾以为我能带给大家 免于战争的自由…
I thought I could give you freedom from war but...
不过 我错了 这种自由不是我能给的
...I was wrong. It's not mine to give.
我们还是很年轻的星球
We're still a young planet.
外面的银河系还有…
There are galaxies out there...
其他的文明 可让我们探寻 供我们学习
...other civilizations for us to meet, to learn from.
我们的未来将是光明的
What a brilliant future we could have.
等到我们这星球的人民 开始真正的…
And there will be peace when the people of the world...
企盼和平时…
...want it so badly...
所有政府就不得不 给予人民和平的生活
...their governments will have to give it to them.
我希望大家都能看到 我眼中的地球…
I wish you could see the Earth the way that I see it...
因为只要仔细看着地球 就会发现 地球真的是一个大家庭
...because when you really look at it, it's just one world.
你想他会找到我们吗？
Do you think he'll find us?
不可能 我们先沉潜一阵子…
Never. We'll lay low for a while...
过几年 我再想个新的计划出来
...a couple of years. I'll come up with a new plan.
还好我有带我的鼓
Good thing I bought my drums.
雷克斯伯伯 你不会相信的…
Uncle Lex, you're not gonna believe this...
- 不过 是超人  - 超人
- ...but it's Superman!  - Superman!
(男孩之家)
- 嘿 酷毙了  - 早安 神父
- Hey, this rocks!  - Morning, Father.
这个小孩受到不良的影响 你能协助他改邪归正吗？
This kid's been under a bad influence. Can you help?
- 每一个孩子都可以矫正  - 我想你是正确的
- Every boy can be helped.  - I think you're right.
- 祝你幸运 孩子  - 跟我来 朋友
- Good luck, son.  - Come with me, friend.
你们该不会有鼓可打吧？
You wouldn't happen to have a drum set?
嘿 莫札特回来了
Hey, Mozart's back!
- 老歪 莫札特回来了  - 我看到了 老土
- Duane, Mozart's back!  - I see him, Bubba!
闭嘴
Shut up!
- 好了 警官 带他走  - 谢谢你 超人 过来 路瑟
- All right, take him away.  - Thank you. Come on, Luthor.
- 只问一件事 你怎么打败他的？  - 高中物理
- Just one thing, how did you beat him?  - High school physics.
我正好有点时间想到…
I had time to figure out...
如果那东西是从太阳生出来的 就一定是太阳给的能量
...that if it was born from the sun, that had to be its energy.
- 世界会被蒸发掉吗？  - 不会的 路瑟
- Is the world gonna be vaporized?  - No, Luthor.
事情总是这样的 总在危险边缘 正义迎战邪恶
It's as it always was, on the brink, with good fighting evil.
20年后再见了
See you in 20.